On April seventh, twenty twenty six, Anthropic disclosed Claude Mythos Preview and Project Glasswing.
The important signal is not one model name.
It is that autonomous cyber capability is now credible enough to compress vulnerability discovery, exploitation, and defensive response cycles.
Quarry is built for this new clock: machine-speed investigation with human governance.
The analyst starts with a natural-language brief.
In this demo, the case is organized Pix fraud at a fictitious Brazilian fintech called FinPlay Pagamentos.
The brief describes five hundred suspicious transactions in thirty days, with newly created accounts receiving fragmented values and redistributing them to potential mule accounts.
Quarry decomposes the brief into testable hypotheses.
It does not jump directly to an answer.
It proposes a mule-account ring, a possible SIM-swap origin for a high-value account, anomalous Open Finance access, and a boleto fraud campaign.
Each hypothesis has a confidence score, expected evidence, and the data sources that should be queried.
The agent now runs controlled queries.
The important product decision is governance. Query execution is visible.
Cost and token usage are visible.
Read-only evaluation paths are enforced for benchmark work.
The Investigation Ledger records the questions, the evidence, and the reasoning path so the analyst can challenge or reproduce the result.
The system correlates events into findings.
Here, the suspicious flow crosses twenty newly created accounts, ninety-six thousand Pix events, and more than two hundred fifty thousand reais in correlated value.
Instead of a black-box answer, the analyst receives prioritized findings, related entities, and a graph that explains why the case deserves attention.
Quarry then generates an analyst-ready report. The report is not just prose.
It is backed by the ledger: hypotheses, queries, findings, timeline, MITRE context where relevant, and a defensible conclusion.
This is the output a security leader can review, improve, and send forward.
The final reveal is cost and time.
In the demo, Quarry shows machine cost next to an estimated human analyst cost and hours saved.
The claim is not that humans disappear.
The claim is that senior investigation capacity becomes measurable, repeatable, and dramatically faster under human control.